finewoodworking.com 2019-12-10

# Privacy Policy - The Taunton Press

**Last updated: May 25, 2018**  

**OUR PRIVACY COMMITMENT**

We care about your privacy and want you to be informed about what we do. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, and share the information we receive about our clients and consumers and explains the options that are available to you. We’ll try to make this clear and simple, but if you have questions, you can contact us, and we’ll be happy to help. See the “Contact Us” section at the end of this document.

The Taunton Press, Inc. (“Taunton”, “us”, “our” or “we”) has developed this Privacy Policy to detail important information regarding the use and disclosure of user information collected on the websites that are owned and operated by Taunton.  These sites include, but are not limited to, finewoodworking.com, finehomebuilding.com, finegardening.com, finecooking.com, greenbuildingadvisor.com, threadsmagazine.com, tauntonstore.com and any successor websites (collectively and individually the “Site(s)”), and other interactive properties, including but not limited to our mobile applications (the Sites and other Taunton interactive properties are collectively referred to herein as the “Taunton Applications”).  This Privacy Policy also applies to our offline collection of information.  Thus, this Privacy Policy applies to your use of (1) Taunton Applications (however accessed and/or used, whether via personal computers, mobile devices, or otherwise); (2) Taunton email or electronic newsletters; (3) offline use, such as by telephone and traditional mail; and (4) any other means or applications on which you connect with us or our products and services.

This Privacy Policy found at _[_http://www.taunton.com/privacy-policy_](http://www.taunton.com/privacy-policy)_ is incorporated into and subject to Taunton’s [Terms of Use](http://www.taunton.com/terms-of-use).  Each time you access or use Taunton Applications you signify that you have read, understand, and agree to be bound by the [Terms of Use](http://www.taunton.com/terms-of-use) and this Privacy Policy.  If you do not agree to the [Terms of Use](http://www.taunton.com/terms-of-use) and this Privacy Policy, you must discontinue using Taunton Applications.

**To Users Resident in the European Economic Area:**   This Privacy Policy will govern use of your personal information if you choose to use any of the Taunton Applications.  However, your specific rights as European Union data subjects (“EU Data Rights”) are addressed below in the section titled, “ _Privacy Rights of Users in the European Economic Area (EEA_)“.

**HOW WE COLLECT PERSONAL INFORMATION**

This section describes the kinds of personal information we collect about you in connection with your use of Taunton Applications.

**Information You Provide To Us**

  * **Contacting Us.** When you provide us with information in connection with a particular activity or otherwise sign up for our services or provide your contact information, including an email address or telephone number in connection with that activity, product, or service, you agree that this action constitutes a transaction or inquiry establishing a business relationship with us.  You expressly consent to our communicating with you future information about Taunton using the information you provided to us.  You also attest that you have the legal authority over any telephone number you provide to us and can provide us with the authorization to contact you.  This means we may contact you, in person or by recorded message, by e-mail, telephone and/or mobile telephone number (including use of automated dialing equipment), text (SMS) message, or any other means of communication that your wireless or other telecommunications device may be capable of receiving.  You may withdraw your consent to any or all of these communications at any time by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” button or other means offered in a communication, or by contacting us at _privacy@taunton.com._
  * **Registration Information.** We will collect personally identifiable information from you when you register for any Taunton membership sites, interact with our Taunton Applications, update your profile, interact with other users, and/or use various features of our Taunton Applications.  By signing up, you give us permission to store and display user information you have provided in order to provide the best possible experience on Taunton Applications.
  * **Billing Information.** We collect and store billing and credit card information.  This information will only be shared with third parties who perform tasks required to complete the transaction. Examples of this include fulfilling orders and processing credit cards.
  * **Surveys and Promotions** **.** From time-to-time we may request information from you and other users via surveys, contests, or sweepstakes.  Participation in these surveys, contests, or sweepstakes is completely voluntary so you and other users have a choice whether or not to disclose this information.  The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and address), and demographic information (such as zip code).  Contact information may be used to notify the winners, award prizes, and file winners’ information as required by law.  Survey information will be used for the purpose(s) of the survey, including the monitoring or improvement of the use and satisfaction of Taunton Applications.
  * **User Generated Content** **.**  Please remember that any information you disclose while participating on public e-mail services, chat areas, messaging or communication tools, or other interactive forums accessed through Taunton Applications, which are designed to facilitate your communication with others or post content on the Sites (“Communication Services”), becomes public information, becomes the property of, and is subject to redistribution by Taunton.  You should exercise caution and discretion when deciding to disclose your personal information in a submission or posting.  There is no expectation of privacy when playing, posting, or otherwise participating on the Communication Services to protect the integrity of Taunton Applications and meet our obligations under applicable laws. If you post content, such as messages, photos, and videos please be aware that any personally identifiable information contained in such content is accessible to registered users or visitors to that Taunton Application or Communication Service, and we have no control over how those users may use your personally identifiable information.  We have the right, but not the obligation, to monitor any activity and content associated with the Communication Services.  We reserve the right to take action in connection with any content we deem to be inappropriate.  Please review our [Terms of Use](http://www.taunton.com/terms-of-use) for more information regarding your appropriate use of these areas.

**Information Collected Through Technology**

In addition to any personally identifiable information or other information that you choose to submit to us, we and our third-party service providers may use a variety of technologies that automatically (or passively) collect certain information whenever you visit or interact with Taunton Applications (“Usage Information”).  This may include the browser that you are using, the URL that referred you to Taunton Applications, all of the areas within Taunton Applications that you visit, and the time of day, among other information.  We may use this Usage Information for a variety of purposes, including enhancing or otherwise improving Taunton Applications.  In addition, we collect your IP address or other unique identifier (“Device Identifier”) for your computer or other device used to access Taunton Applications (any, a “Device”).  A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to the device used to access Taunton Applications, and our computers identify your device by its Device Identifier.  Usage Information may be non-identifying or may be associated with you.  Whenever we associate Usage Information or a Device Identifier with your personal information, we will treat it as personally identifiable information.  However, some information collected in this manner may be non-personally identifiable information, and may be used for analytical purposes only.

A few of the tracking technologies that may be used to collect Usage Information include, without limitation, the following:

**Cookies.**   A cookie is a data file placed on a Device when it is used to visit the Site.  Cookies may be used for many purposes, including, without limitation, remembering you and your preferences and tracking your visits to our web pages.  We use cookies to collect information for record keeping purposes and to make it easier to navigate the Site.  Cookies are stored on users’ hard drives.  We use both “session ID cookies” and “persistent cookies.” Session ID cookies are used to store information while a user is logged into the Site and expire when the user closes his/her browser.  Persistent cookies are used to make tasks like logging into the Site easier for returning users by remembering a user’s login information. Persistent cookies stay on a user’s hard drive from one session to the next.  You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a persistent or session cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off such cookies through your browser settings.  Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

We use cookies to enable functions on our website, personalize content and ads, provide social media features, and to analyze our website traffic.  We also share information about your use of our website with third party social media, advertising, and analytics organizations that may combine it with other information that you’ve provided to them or that they’ve collected from your use of their services.

The cookies we use fall into the following categories:

**Essential.**  These cookies help make our websites usable by enabling basic functions like page navigation and access to secure areas of the website.  The website cannot function properly without these cookies.

**Advertising.** ** ** These cookies allow us to know whether or not you’ve seen an advertisement or a type of advertisement, and how long it is since you’ve seen it. **  **We also use cookies for the purposes of targeted advertising.  We may use cookies set by a third party so we can more accurately target advertising to you.  For example, we may show an advertisement about woodworking tools if you have recently visited the tool section of our woodworking site.  These cookies are anonymous – they store information about what you are looking at on our site, but not who you are.

Some of the advertisements you see on our websites are provided by third party organizations.  Some of these organizations use their own anonymous cookies to track how many people have seen a particular ad, or to track how many people have seen it more than once.  The companies that generate these cookies have their own privacy policies, which we do not have access to.  These organizations may use their cookies to anonymously target advertising to you on other websites, based on your visit to Taunton websites.

Social networking cookies are used to enable you to share pages and content that you find interesting on our websites through third party social networking and other websites.  These cookies may also be used for advertising purposes.

**Analytics.** ** ** These cookies help us track site metrics and user behavior behind the scenes to improve and optimize our sites.  This data includes information about what pages were visited, what links were clicked, what terms were searched for, and provides information on the success of our marketing campaigns.  This data is used to help determine how our websites can be customized to provide a better user experience.  All of the information these cookies collect is anonymous and is only used to improve how our website works.

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings.  To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set, visit [ _www.aboutcookies.org_](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) or [ _www.allaboutcookies.org_](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Find out how to manage cookies on popular browsers:

To find information relating to other browsers, visit the browser developer’s website.

**Web Beacons.**  Small graphic images or other web programming code called web beacons (also known as “1×1 GIFs” or “clear GIFs”) may be included in our web pages and messages.  Web beacons may be invisible to you, but any electronic image or other web programming code inserted into a web page or e-mail can act as a web beacon.  Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count visitors to our Sites, to monitor how users navigate the Sites, to count how many e-mails that were sent were actually opened, or to count how many particular articles or links were actually viewed.

**Embedded Script.**  An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with Taunton Applications, such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your Device from our web server or a third-party service provider, is active only while you are connected to the Sites, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.

**Information You Provide About a Third Party**

If you send someone else a communication from Taunton Applications, such as sending an invitation to a friend, the information you provide (names, e-mail addresses, etc.) is used to facilitate the communication and is not used for any other marketing purpose, unless we obtain consent from that person, or we explicitly say otherwise.  If that person becomes a subscriber to our publications, his/her information will be treated in the same manner as all other subscribers.  Please be aware that when you use any send-to-a-friend functionality on Taunton Applications, your e-mail address may be included in the communication sent to your friend.

**Information We Collect From Third Parties**  
We may acquire information from other trusted sources to update or supplement the information you provided or that we collected automatically, such as information to validate or update your address or other demographic and lifestyle information.  We use this information to help us maintain the accuracy of the information we collect, to target our communications so that we can inform you of products, services and offers that may be of interest, and for internal business analysis or other business purposes.

**Third-Party Analytics Technologies**  
We use third-party analytics and other tools to better understand who is using Taunton Applications, how people are using Taunton Applications and how to improve the effectiveness of Taunton Applications and their content, and to help us serve more targeted content and advertising to you.  Those third-party companies may use cookies, pixel tags, or other technologies to collect and store anonymous information such as time of visit, pages visited, time spent on each page of the Taunton Applications, Device Identifiers, type of operating system and browser used, and other web sites you may have visited.  We do not have access to, nor control over, third parties’ use of cookies or other tracking technologies.

**HOW WE USE AND SHARE YOUR INFORMATION**

**Use of Information by Us**

We may use information that we collect about you:  (1) to provide you with information or services or process transactions that you have requested or agreed to receive;  (2) to provide you with information regarding new features, products or services;  (3) to improve Taunton Applications or your use of these Applications and to customize your experience;  (4) to contact you with regard to your use of the Site and, in our discretion, changes to the Site and/or the Site’s policies;  (5) for internal business purposes; and (6) for purposes disclosed at the time you provide your information or as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy.

We will only process your personal information (including sharing it with third parties), when  (1) you have given us your consent (which you can withdraw at any time),  (2) the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party,  (3) we are required to do so by law, (iv) processing is required to protect your vital interests or those of another person, or  (v) processing is necessary for our legitimate commercial interests, unless those interests are overridden by your rights and interests.

**Transactional Communications**

We may send you notices from time to time relating to your account or your subscriptions.  These may include order confirmations, renewal notices, invoices, or customer service notifications.  We may also send you service-related announcements when it is necessary to do so; for instance, if our Site(s) is temporarily suspended for maintenance, or the delivery of a product is delayed, or there is some service issue with something you may have ordered. You may not opt-out of receiving these communications which are necessary to the operation of our service and are not promotional in nature.

**Service Providers**

We may use third-party service providers to help us operate our business and Taunton Applications or administer activities on our behalf.  We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes.

**Electronic Promotional Offers**

We may send you promotional emails regarding special offers about our publications or services, or on behalf of third-party marketing partners who we think can offer services and products of interest to you.  We will not share your personally identifiable information or other information about you, such as when you first subscribed, with any other companies that provide marketing offers through email; however, we may provide targeted promotional offers on behalf of other companies based on the information you have provided to us.  If you do not want to receive emails regarding special promotions or offers, you may contact us at any time at (866) 242-4199 for the USA and Canada, Monday – Friday 9:00 AM to 9:00 PM Eastern Standard Time; and +1 (515) 247-2990 for all other international calls, or you may click the Unsubscribe link in the body of the email, updating your preferences and pressing Save Your Preferences, or go directly to the preference center at <http://www.taunton.com/preferences>.

Please note that even if you opt-out of receiving promotional e-mails, we may continue to send you electronic service notifications that are related to your account(s) and other products and services you have requested or in which you are currently enrolled.

**Direct Mail Promotional Offers**

If you are a print subscriber to our publications and you subscribed either by mail, [online](https://www.taunton.com/eCommerce/CS/cs_privacy_change.aspx), or other method, we may send you offers through direct mail that we feel might be of interest to you and/or we may rent your name and mailing address and certain other information with reputable companies that provide marketing offers through direct mail.  If you do not want us to send you any offers from third parties through direct mail, or rent your personal information with other companies so that they can send you direct mail offers about their products and services, please contact Customer Service at (866) 242-4199 for the USA and Canada, Monday – Friday 9:00 AM to 9:00 PM Eastern Standard Time; or +1 (515) 247-2990 for all other international calls.  You may also write to us at the street address provided in the Contact Us section at the end of this document, or email us at _[_privacy@taunton.com_](mailto:privacy@taunton.com)_.  If you are a current print subscriber, please remember to include your account number, mailing address, and phone number in the body of your email or letter, and if you choose to opt-out via e-mail, please include “Direct Mail Opt-Out” in the subject line. Please note that even if you opt-out of receiving promotional direct mail offers, we may continue to send you service notifications that are related to your account(s) and other products and services you have requested or in which you are currently enrolled by direct mail.

**Third-Party Advertising**

We also use third-party ad servers and ad networks to serve advertisements when you visit the Sites.  These companies, and the advertisers themselves, may use information about your visits on other web sites and our Sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.  In the course of serving advertisements to our Sites, these third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your Device, the advertisements and links that appear on the Sites. They automatically receive your Device Identifier when this happens. They may also use tracking technologies to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content.  This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such advertisers, ad servers, or ad networks. You should consult the respective privacy policies of any advertisers on our Sites to see your options for opting out of their use of such devices.

**Opting Out of Third Party Advertising.** **  **

In addition, some of the ad servers and ad networks may be members of the Network Advertising Initiative, which offers a single location to opt-out of ad targeting from member companies.  If you opt-out of receiving targeted ads on our Sites from ad servers and ad networks, you may continue to receive advertising and promotional messages after you opt-out, but it will not be customized or personalized to you based on your use of our Sites and/or third-party websites.

If you would like more information about advertisers’ use of tracking technologies and about your option not to accept these cookies, you can go to:  [ _http://optout.networkadvertising.org/_](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).  If you would like to learn more about how interest-based information is collected, whether the companies we use are part of an industry network regarding behavioral advertising, and to know your choices about not having information used in this manner, you can go to: _[_http://www.aboutads.info/consumers_](http://www.aboutads.info/consumers)_.

**Co-Branded Areas**

Certain areas on our Sites may be provided to you in association with third parties such as sponsors or advertisers (“Co-Branded Areas”) and may request that you disclose personal information to them.  Such Co-Branded Areas will identify the third party.  If you elect to register for products and/or services at Co-Branded Areas, you may be providing your information to both us and the third party. Your personal information will be subject to this Privacy Policy as well as the privacy policy and practices of such third party.  We are not responsible for the privacy policy or practices of such third party.  You should consult the respective privacy policies of those third party sponsors or advertisers to learn more about their privacy practices.

**Sweepstakes, Contests, and Promotions**

We may offer sweepstakes, contests, and other promotions (a “Promotion”) through Taunton Applications that may require registration.  By participating in a Promotion, you are agreeing to official rules that govern that Promotion.  When you enter a Promotion, we may ask for personally identifiable information including your name, address, and email address so that we can administer the Promotion and notify winners.  If you choose to enter a Promotion, such personal information may be disclosed to third parties or to the public in connection with the administration of such Promotion, including, without limitation, in connection with winner selection, prize fulfillment, and as required by law, such as on a winners’ list or as permitted by the Promotion’s official rules.  Also, by entering the Promotion, you are agreeing to the official rules that govern the Promotion, which may contain specific requirements of you, including except where prohibited by law, allowing the sponsor(s) of the Promotion to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing associated with the Promotion.

**Legal Matters; Safety**

We may, without your consent, access and disclose your information, any communications sent or received by you (including, without limitation, the contents of any chat, messaging, or other communication posted in the Communication Services), and any other information that we may have about you or your account as may be permitted or required by law (including, but not limited to, court order or subpoena), or to prevent or investigate suspected fraud or violations of our [Terms of Use](http://www.taunton.com/terms-of-use) or activity that appear to us to be illegal, or that may expose us to legal liability. Additionally, we may disclose your information and/or communications in situations that we believe to be: (1) emergencies involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person or property if we believe that your information in any way relates to that threat; or (2) your conduct on Taunton Applications or when using the Communication Services that we believe is inappropriate and inconsistent with generally accepted norms of behavior.

**Sale or Transfer of Business or Assets**

In the event that we, or any of our businesses, are sold or disposed of as a going concern, whether by merger, sale of assets, or otherwise, or in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership, personally identifiable information of our visitors may be one of the assets sold or merged in connection with that transaction.  Information about our visitors and registered users may also need to be disclosed in connection with a commercial transaction where we or any one of our businesses are seeking financing, investment, support, or funding.  In such transactions, personal information will be subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Policy in effect when the information was obtained.

**ACCOUNT DEACTIVATION; ACCESS TO YOUR INFORMATION**

If for any reason you would like to change any personal information you provided to us, or deactivate any account with us, please contact Customer Service at (866) 242-4199 for the USA and Canada, Monday – Friday 9:00 AM to 9:00 PM Eastern Standard Time; or +1 (515) 247-2990 for all other international calls; or email us at _[_privacy@taunton.com_](mailto:privacy@taunton.com)_ **.  **We will be happy to review, update, or remove information as appropriate.

If you deactivate your account, you will not be able to sign in to our Taunton Applications or access any of your personal information, but you can open a new, separate account at any time.  If you deactivate your account, we may still retain certain information associated with your account for analytical purposes and record keeping integrity, as well as to prevent fraud, resolve disputes, enforce our [Terms of Use](http://www.taunton.com/terms-of-use) or other policies, or take actions we deem necessary due to technical and legal requirements and constraints related to the security, integrity, and operation of our Taunton Applications.

If you would like to delete your personally identifiable information collected through our Sites, please contact us at _[_privacy@taunton.com_](mailto:privacy@taunton.com)_ , or call us at (866) 242-4199 for the USA and Canada, Monday – Friday 9:00 AM to 9:00 PM Eastern Standard Time; or +1 (515) 247-2990 for all other international calls. You may write to us at:

**The Taunton Press, Inc.**  
c/o CDS  
P.O. Box 37610  
Boone, Iowa  50037-0610  USA  
**Attention: Customer Service**

In addition, if certain information has already been provided to third parties as described in this Privacy Policy, we will take all reasonable steps to notify the third parties that you have requested your data be deleted, but we cannot guarantee that all third parties will honor our request.

**A Note to Users Who Are EU Data Subjects** :  Notwithstanding the previous paragraph, your rights related to your personal information processed by us, and our use and retention of your personal information are subject to your EU Data Rights as described in this _Privacy Policy_ **.**

**CHOICE AND OPT-OUT**

You may remove your information from our database so as to not receive future communications, or to close your account, or opt-out of our sharing information with third parties for marketing purposes by emailing us at _[_privacy@taunton.com_](mailto:privacy@taunton.com)_ or sending snail mail (certified mail, return receipt requested is recommended) to the following address:

**The Taunton Press, Inc.  
**c/o CDS  
P.O. Box 37610  
Boone, Iowa  50037-0610  USA  
**Attention:  Customer Service **

If you prefer not to receive electronic promotional communications, you can opt-out by following the Unsubscribe instructions included in each communication.

Please note that changes may not be effective immediately.  In each event, you must clearly indicate the information that you wish to have changed, or clearly indicate that you wish to have your personally identifiable information removed from our database.  We will endeavor to comply with your request as soon as reasonably possible.  Finally, we will take all reasonable steps, but cannot guarantee, that we can inform all third parties (including without limitation our third-party service providers or strategic partners) with whom we have already shared your personally identifiable information of any changes requested pursuant to this section, or for removing information from or causing information to be removed from the databases or records of such entities.

**A Note to Users Who Are EU Data Subjects** :  Notwithstanding the previous paragraph, your rights related to your personal information processed by us, and our use and retention of your personal information, are subject to your EU Data Rights as described in this _Privacy Policy_.

**IMPORTANT DISCLOSURES, PRACTICES, AND CONTACT INFORMATION**

**Links to Other Sites and Communities**  
To the extent hyperlinks may be utilized to access external or third-party sites and communities, you should be aware that these external or third-party site and communities are not controlled by us and, therefore, are not subject to this Privacy Policy.  We recommend that you check the privacy policies of each such site and community to determine how your personal information will be utilized by their proprietors.

**Security**

We implement safeguards to help protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of information under our control.  However, despite our efforts, no data transmission over the Internet, wireless transmission or electronic storage of information can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  Please note that we cannot ensure the security of any information you transmit to us, and your use of the Site indicates that you are willing to assume this risk. ****

**Privacy Rights of Users in the European Economic Area (EEA)**

Under the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (“GDPR”), effective as of May 25, 2018, European Union data subjects are entitled to certain specific rights with respect to processing of their personal data.

Under the GDPR, in certain circumstances, you have the right to:

  * Request access to your personal information;
  * Request the correction of inaccurate or incomplete personal information;
  * Request that your personal information be erased;
  * Object to the processing of your personal information, including processing for direct marketing purposes;
  * Request that the processing of your personal information be restricted;
  * Request that you receive your personal information in order to transfer it to another data controller;
  * Withdraw at any time your consent to the use of your personal information;
  * Make a complaint to an EU Data Protection Authority where you believe that we have not complied with our obligations under this Privacy Policy or applicable European data protection law (including the GDPR); and
  * We will not transfer your personal information to third parties located outside of the EEA without taking steps to ensure adequate protection under the GDPR.  If a third party is located in a country not recognized by the EU Commission as providing an adequate level of protection, we will use appropriate measures, such as entering into standard contractual clauses, approved by the EU Commission, to protect your personal information.

You may exercise any of the above rights by contacting us at _[_privacy@taunton.com_](mailto:privacy@taunton.com)_ or writing to us at the address in the Contact Us section at the end of this document.

**A Note to Non-EU International Users**

The Taunton Applications are operated in the United States and are intended for users located in the United States.  However, we have developed policies and implemented practices to comply with regulations in the European Union and in Canada.  If you are located anywhere else outside of the United States, please be aware that information we collect will be transferred to, processed, and stored in the United States.  The data protection laws in the United States may differ from those of the country in which you are located, and your personal information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in the United States according to laws of the United States.  By using Taunton Applications or by providing us with any information, you consent to this transfer, processing, and storage of your information in the United States.  You are also consenting to the application of United States federal and Connecticut state law in all matters concerning the Site and this Privacy Policy.

**Your Consent to Transfer Your Personal Information to Our Website** **.**   If you are visiting our site from outside the United States, please be aware that your information will be transferred to, processed, and stored in the United States where our servers and central databases are located.  By your agreement to use the Communication Services and acceptance of this Privacy Policy, you consent to such transfer of your personal information for use in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**How Long We Store Your Information.** **  **Unless we have deleted your information in accordance with your request pursuant to this Privacy Policy, we will retain your information for so long as your account is active or as needed to provide you any of the services.  If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information, please email us at _[_privacy@taunton.com_](mailto:privacy@taunton.com)_ or call us at (866) 242-4199 for the USA and Canada, Monday – Friday 9:00 AM to 9:00 PM Eastern Standard Time; or +1 (515) 247-2990 for all other international calls.  However, we will retain and use your information to the extent necessary to comply with applicable laws, resolve disputes, or enforce our contractual rights.

**California Privacy Rights**

California’s “Shine the Light” law, Civil Code section 1798.83, requires certain businesses to respond to requests from California customers asking about their business practices related to disclosing personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. Alternately, such businesses may have in place a policy not to disclose personal information of customers to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes if the customer has exercised an option to opt-out of such information-sharing.  We have such a policy in place.  If you do not want us to send you emails regarding special promotions or offers or share your personal information with other companies so that they can send you emails about their products and services, simply follow the Unsubscribe instructions that are located at the bottom of those emails, or you may email us at _[_privacy@taunton.com_](mailto:privacy@taunton.com)_ or call us at (866) 242-4199 for the USA and Canada, Monday – Friday 9:00 AM to 9:00 PM Eastern Standard Time; or +1 (515) 247-2990 for all other international calls.  California customers may request further information about our approach to this law also by writing to us at the address provided in the Contact Us section at the end of this document.

**Children’s Privacy**

The Taunton Applications are for a general purpose audience and are not directed or intended for children under 13 years of age.  We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from individuals under 13 years of age.  If you are under 13 years of age, you should not register or provide personally identifiable information on Taunton Applications.  If we later obtain actual knowledge that a user is under 13 years of age, we will take steps to remove that user’s personally identifiable information from our systems.

**Changes to the Privacy Policy**

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time.  The most recent version of the Privacy Policy will always be posted on our Sites, with the “Effective Date” posted at the top of the Policy. We may revise and update this Privacy Policy if our practices change, as technology changes, or as we add new Taunton Applications, or Community Services, or change existing ones.  If we make any material changes to our Privacy Policy or how we handle your personal information, you will know because the Effective Date of the Privacy Policy will change.  If we are going to use any personal information in a manner that is materially different from that stated in our Privacy Policy at the time we collected such information, we will give you a reasonable opportunity to consent to the change.  If you do not consent, your personal information will be used as agreed to under the terms of the privacy policy in effect at the time we obtained that information.  We will use information previously obtained in accordance with the privacy policy in effect when the information was obtained from you **.  **

**Disputes**

If you choose to visit Taunton Applications, your visit and any dispute over privacy, excluding matters that are required to be resolved before European data protection authorities pursuant to European Union data protection law (including the GDPR), is subject to this Privacy Policy and our [Terms of Use](http://www.taunton.com/terms-of-use) including limitations on damages, resolution of disputes, and application of the laws of the United States and the State of Connecticut **.**

**No Rights of Third Parties**

This Privacy Policy does not create rights enforceable by third parties or require disclosure of any personal information relating to users of the website.

**HOW TO CONTACT US**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the practices of the Taunton Applications and Community Services, please send your email queries to _[_privacy@taunton.com_](mailto:privacy@taunton.com)_ , or call us at (866) 242-4199 for the USA and Canada, Monday – Friday 9:00 AM to 9:00 PM Eastern Standard Time; or +1 (515) 247-2990 for all other international calls. You may write to us at:

**The Taunton Press, Inc.  
c/o CDS**  
**P.O. Box 37610**  
**Boone, Iowa   50037-0610  USA**  
**Attention:   Customer Service **

Copyright © 2018   The Taunton Press, Inc.  All rights reserved.  
Last Updated:  May 25, 2018
